
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>程序员资源分享网站</title>
      <link>https://goto-share.github.io/blog</link>
      <description>内容来自耗子维护的 Telegram 程序员资源分享群, 本群主要是技术资源分享，包括：技术资料、资源、工具、心得、热点等
为了让交流更多效率：1）鼓励有价值的内容、有深度的思考; 2）鼓励友善、互相帮助、努力学习的氛围；3）不要做伸手党、盗版党、破解党；4）提问前先看看《提问的智慧》； 5) 适当聊天讨论翻墙，千万不要灌水； 6）禁止开车、广告和商业推广； 7）禁止任何仇恨、煽动、歧视的言论； 8）禁止有政治、宗教、性别攻击倾向的言论； 9）禁止低级趣味下流庸俗的内容
  </description>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <managingEditor>dylanninin@gmail.com (@haoel)</managingEditor>
      <webMaster>dylanninin@gmail.com (@haoel)</webMaster>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
      <atom:link href="https://goto-share.github.io/tags/ssd/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      
  <item>
    <guid>https://goto-share.github.io/blog/2021-03-07-872</guid>
    <title>How do SSDs Work?
</title>
    <link>https://goto-share.github.io/blog/2021-03-07-872</link>
    <description>Have you ever wondered how your smartphone can store countless pictures, songs, or videos?  Or, have you wondered when you download a podcast to your smartphone, where does it actually get stored?  In this video, we will open up your smartphone and take a look at the inside of the memory storage microchip.  This same microchip is also used to store data in solid-state drives, or SSDs in your computer, in tablets, and inside flash drives.  The technology is called VNAND or V-NAND, and it&#39;s incredible how engineers were able to fit such an insane amount of memory storage capacity in such a small space.  Do you want to support in-depth engineering and technology education? Support us on: https://www.patreon.com/brancheducation   Website: https://www.branch.education  On Facebook: https://www.facebook.com/BranchEducation/  On Twitter: https://twitter.com/TeddyTablante  On Insta: https://www.instagram.com/brancheducation/  Or Join us on YouTube Memberships: https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCdp4_l1vPmpN-gDbUwhaRUQ/join  Written, animated, and edited- Teddy Tablante   Twitter: @teddytablante Voice Over- Phil Lee  Timestamps:   0:00 - Intro into SSDs 2:06 - Example of Saving a Picture 4:17 - Pixel Calculations 5:19 - Single Memory Cell 7:59 - Vertical Strings and Pages 10:34 - Control Gates of VNAND 12:00 - Calculations of Example Array 13:09 - True size of an SSD microchip  14:50 - Overall chip in an SSD 16:07 - Outro 16:32 - Creator&#39;s comments 16:54 - Future Episodes  This video is part of a series that intends to thoroughly explain how SSDs, and more specifically how VNAND works.  These are the episodes in the series:  1) [18min] Overview on how SSDs / VNAND / Smartphone storage works.  2) [3min] Quick/Abridged episode of the overview  3) How charge trap flash works.  (details on a single memory cell)  4) How strings of memory cells work (details on a stack of memory cells)  5) How a massive array of memory cells are organized. (Terabit Cell Array Transistor, TCAT)  6) How is VNAND manufactured?  7) Possible episode on an analogy using a city &amp; apartments to explain VNAND.  Key Branches from this video are: Microchips, CPUs, Integrated Circuits,  Erratum:    Animation built using Blender 2.82a https://www.blender.org/  Post with Adobe Premiere Pro  Book References: Aritome, Seiichi. (2015).  NAND flash memory technologies.  IEEE Press Series on Microelectronic Systems.  Wiley.  [2nd most useful resource]    Cai, Yu et al.  (2013) Threshold Voltage Distribution in MLC NAND Flash Memory:  Characterization Analysis, and Modeling.  2013 Design, Automation &amp; Test in Europe Conference &amp; Exhibition.  IEEE.  Micheloni, Rino.  Marelli, Alessia.  Eshghi, Kam. (2018)  Inside solid state drives (SSDs) Second edition.  Springer Series in Advanced Microelectronics Volume 37. Springer.    Micheloni, Rino.  (2017) Solid-state-drives (SSDs) Modeling, Simulation tools &amp; strategies.  Springer Series in Advanced Microelectronics Volume 58.  Springer  Micheloni, Rino. Crippa, Luca. (2016) 3D flash memories. Springer.   [Chapter 4- Most useful resource]   Pierret, Robert F. (1996)  Semiconductor Device Fundamentals. Addison-Wesley Publishing Company.  Prince, Betty.  (2014) Vertical 3D Memory Technologies.  Wiley  Internet References: Crisp, Simon. (29/01/2018)  Samsung SSD860 PRO 4TB SSD Review.  Kitguru.net https://www.kitguru.net/components/ssd-drives/simon-crisp/samsung-ssd860-pro-4tb-ssd-review/all/1/ (Accessed 07/05/2020)  Mellor, Chris. (28/07/2016) QLC flash istricky stuff to make and use, so here&#39;s a primer.  TheRegister.co.uk https://www.theregister.co.uk/2016/07/28/qlc_flash_primer/ (Accessed 07/05/2020)  Samsung Website.  Samsung 1TB Details and Specifications www.samsung.com https://www.samsung.com/us/computing/memory-storage/solid-state-drives/ssd-860-evo-2-5--sata-iii-1tb-mz-76e1t0b-am/ (Accessed 07/05/2020)  Shah, Dhiram. (27/02/2019) Samsung Begins Mass Production of Frist 512 GB eUFS3.0 for Next-Generation Mobile Devices. Fareastgizmos.com https://fareastgizmos.com/smartphone/samsung-begins-mass-production-of-first-512gb-eufs-3-0…
</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dylanninin@gmail.com (@haoel)</author>
    <category>youtube</category><category>ssd</category>
  </item>

  <item>
    <guid>https://goto-share.github.io/blog/2021-03-07-873</guid>
    <title>Coding for SSDs – Part 1: Introduction and Table of Contents
</title>
    <link>https://goto-share.github.io/blog/2021-03-07-873</link>
    <description>I want to make solid-state drives (SSDs) the optimal storage solution for my key-value store project. For that reason, I had to make sure I fully understood how SSDs work
</description>
    <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <author>dylanninin@gmail.com (@haoel)</author>
    <category>ssd</category>
  </item>

    </channel>
  </rss>
